

Atilio Villalba Giubi

Asunción, Paraguay

atiliovg94@gmail.com

+595981247960

github.com/ajvg94

in ajvg94

10/06/1994

Paraguayan

₽ Profile

I specialize in developing various types of software such as web applications, desktop software and APIs. I have worked on a variety of projects ranging from small to large scale applications utilizing latest technologies and frameworks.

My experience includes working as a developer for different remote development teams, both within Latin America and beyond. The main areas that I have expertise in include JavaScript, Node.js, TypeScript, ReactJS and databases, I also have some experience working with Python and C# in personal projects.

I enjoy being challenged by tough problems and I'm always on the lookout for new opportunities. I am highly motivated to keep up with the newest technologies and innovations, ensuring the quality of my projects delivered to customers.

Education

02/2012 - 08/2020

Universidad Catolica Nuestra Señora de la Asunción,

Lambare, Paraguay

Graduated as Computer Science Engineer



Skills

Node JS

Express

Databases

PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, ArangoDB, Redis (No-SQL)

SO's

Linux, Windows

Unit Testing

Mocha, Chai, Sinon, NYC

Frontend

React JS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Jquery

Message Brokers

RabbitMQ, Apache Kafka

Others

JavaScript, Typescript, Docker, Python

atiliovg94@gmail.com

1/3



Spanish English French

Professional Experience

Wind River ☐ Sep 2021 – present Remote

Project: Test Automation Framework | Back End Engineer □

As a member of a remote Agile team, I am currently working mostly as a Backend Developer. The goal of the project is to develop a library of tests that run into multiple platforms (computers, containers, etc.), being able to run them, create multiple workflows and create reports based in the results.

The project has a Backend developed using Node.js, Express and TypeScript. Each request is received at the API gateway microservice, is validated and sent to the proper handler with the help of multiple Apache Kafka message queues. Each microservice then uses a controller and a service to resolve the request in the best possible way; this could involve doing calculations, schedule a test, creating a report, analyzing results, creating and executing and workflow, crud operations, etc.

For all the database or other sources operations, we implemented a data access layer that uses a data factory design pattern. We have multiple data layers, each one of them has their own source mapping that contains all the data sources and actions that can be performed in that data source. Data sources can go from relational, non-relational databases and even external APIs as long as the structure of the data obtained is in the correct format.

We also have unit tests written with the help of libraries like Mocha, Chai and Sinon for Node.js, and the goal is to have a coverage of at least 80% of the code.

As for our workflow, we have daily meetings, weekly backlog grooming meetings where we try to clear any doubts about the upcoming user stories and sprints, demos with the client at the end of each sprint and retrospective meetings at the end of the demo to see what we can improve for the next sprint. We use tools like JIRA, Confluence, Slack and Zoom to stay up to date with our current and upcoming tasks and also document them or write tutorials for new team members.

Microtech SA ☑ Mar 2020 – Aug 2021 Asunción, Paraguay Project: Fortaleza Core | *Full Stack Engineer*

- Designed and implemented a data synchronization module on Node.js, RabbitMQ and PM2 to synchronize data between two different CRM systems
- Developed multiple Express.js web services on Windows-based server to be consumed by multiple CRMs
- Developed an API gateway to secure the previously mentioned web services
- Configuration and maintenance of Windows-based servers with multiple endpoints using Node.js, Express.js, RabbitMQ and PM2
- Creation of API docs with Swagger and OpenAPI 3.0
- Developed several JavaScript scripts for Dynamics365 CRM
- Made ETL scripts for a couple databases in C# and TSQL
- Database analysis and development (SQL)
- Project planning and database design
- Defined business logic requirements by communicating with stakeholders

Fiweex ☑ Apr 2019 – Jan 2020 Asunción, Paraguay

Project: Fiweex | Full Stack Developer

- Acted as a full-stack developer for a web-based interface to display customer data to clients using PHP, MySQL and Jquery
- Designed and implemented a microservice that auto generates PDF reports for clients using PHP, MySQL
- Designed and implemented a microservice that sends the previously mentioned reports as emails to the clients
- Designed and implemented a password recovery module using PHP, FPDF, MySQL
- Developed multiple web services to be consumed by CRM
- Designed and implemented new tables and databases for upcoming modules
- Provided technical support to customers

Courses and Certifications

07/2022 EF SET English Certificate 77/100 (C2 Proficient),

EF Standard English Test 🗆

07/2022 **JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures,**

freeCodeCamp ≥

References

Jefry Baltodano, *Software Engineer Technical Lead*, Wind River jbaltodano23@gmail.com

Guillermo Ojeda, *Software Engineer Team Lead*, Microtech guilleovelar@hotmail.com

Esteban Torres, *CEO*, Fiweex esteban@fiweex.com